

# HASINI ISHARA

Metsäkaari 16 B 23, 05460 Hyvinkää, Finland

+358417237126

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/hasini-ishara-94329516b/



https://github.com/hasiniishara

# PROFILE SUMMARY

Certified IT professional with 4 years of experience in software quality assurance and test automation. ISTQB Foundation Level certified, skilled in designing and implementing automated testing frameworks. Known for a logical mindset, problem-solving skills, and commitment to delivering quality outcomes. Seeking opportunities as a Software QA Engineer or Test Automation Engineer to contribute to organizational success.

### EDUCATION

· Bsc. Computer Science

2018-2021

- University of Colombo School of Computing, Colombo, Sri Lanka
- . Comprehensive Master Java Developer

2019 - 2020

Institute of Java Software Engineering-IJSE, Galle, Sri Lanka

#### CERTIFICATION

· Certified Full Stack Web Developer

Dec, 2023 - June, 2024

Al Cloud Academy, Tampere, Finland

. ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level

2023

- International Software Testing Qualifications Board
- Python of Beginners

2023

Centre for Open & Distance Learning (CODL), University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Test Automation Engineer**

March, 2024 - Dec, 2024

Academic Work - Konecranes Finland Oy, Koneenkatu 8, 05800 Hyvinkää

- Automated tests with Robot Framework, integrating OPC UA server for data validation.
- Automated web application testing using JavaScript and Puppeteer.
- Conducted manual testing in a real-world factory environment, validating web application performance during live crane operations.
- Streamlined and optimized the testing process, from planning to execution, ensuring effective quality assurance practices.
- Conducted load testing using JMeter with WebSocket and polling modes.
- Participated in Scrum meetings, contributing to sprint reviews and planning while ensuring testing goals aligned with development milestones.

# **Quality Assurance Engineer- Remote Worker**

April, 2021 - Feb, 2024

OrangeHRM, Colombo, Sri Lanka

- Led a team of 5 QA engineers in creating and executing test plans for multiple software projects.
- Developed and maintained automated test cases, increasing QA efficiency by 40%.
- Standardized Test plans, Test cases, Bug reports, and status reports, boosting productivity by 10%.
- Conducted diverse testing types such as Cross Functional, Integration, User Acceptance, API, Mobile Testing, and UI testing to ensure robust product performance and quality.

# Linguistics Analyst (Transcriber) - Part Time

Oct, 2023 - Dec, 2023

TELUS International AI Finland Oy, Tampere, Finland

• Proficiently transcribed diverse materials, ensuring accuracy and adherence to company standards.

# Trainee Associate Quality Assurance Engineer

Oct, 2020 - April, 2021

Effective Solutions Pvt Ltd. Colombo, Sri Lanka

- Conducted thorough testing of software applications, including functional, regression, integration, and performance testing.
- Executed manual and automated test cases, analyzed result, and reported issues to the project team
- · Performed root cause analysis for defects and collaborated with development teams on corrective actions.
- Actively participated in Agile/Scrum meetings, reporting on testing progress and resolving issues.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages
  - Java, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C, C++
- Testing Tools
  - Test Link, Mantis, Bugzilla, Postman, Selenium, JMeter, Swagger
- Data Visualization Tools
  - Power BI
- Operating Systems
  - Linux, Windows
- · IDE
  - Eclips, VsCode, IntelliJ IDEA, Visual Studio

- Databases
  - MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase
- Project Management Tools
  - Zoho project, Asana, Jira, Confluence
- Other Tools
  - Docker, Jenkins, Git
- Frameworks
  - · React, React, Robot framework, MS Test, TestNG, Puppeteer, Cypress
- · Markup and Styling Languages
  - HTML, CSS

### OTHER SKILLS

- · Interpersonal & Communication skills
- Team Player / Administration
- · Analytical Ability & Critical thinking

- · Leadership / Management
- Organization
- · Problem-Solving Skills

#### CARDS AND PERMISSIONS

· Occupational Safety Card

## LANGUAGE

• English - Fluent

· Finnish - Basic

# INTEREST

Learning New Things

Playing Hockey

#### REFERENCES

 Mr. Safiul Alam Instructor

Al Cloud Academy

Åkerlundinkatu 8, Tampere,

Finland 33100

E-mail: alamsafiul99@gmail.com

Phone: +358405471232

Ms. Niina Isoranta

Consultant Manager

Academic Work

Keilaranta 4, 02150, Espoo

E-mail: niina.isoranta@academicwork.fi

Phone: +358504049438